Claude can also do the hosting now. Like
you can literally just say like host it,
>> you know, and then it will go do that,
you know. I did that for the zero trust
world thing.
>> Best part of Viking when you can just,
you know, critical think, right?
[music]
[laughter]
>> Yeah, dude.
All right, y'all. We've talked about
threat locker ring fencing a lot. We
know how it allows you to set ACL's and
policies for exactly what an application
is allowed to do in your network. But
today, I'm going to tell you how it does
that. Okay, three technologies. Mini
filter drivers, window filtering
platform, and ex version kernel
notification routines. Mini filter
drivers are essentially a co hook or
callback for um IO requests. Okay, so
when you're trying to write or read from
a file, you can create a hook with those
and prove or deny based off of the
threat locker ACL. Windows filtering
platform, similar situation, but for
connect bind uh requests, right? You can
say, okay, hey, is this process allowed
to talk to port 443 over there on the
internet? Yes or no, approve or deny.
Lastly, you've got EX version kernel
notification routines. The EX version is
important because uh it allows you to
approve or deny versus just getting a
notification from the kernel. Um and
this is specific for um hooking various
native API calls like nt create user
process which is what you would use to
like spin up powershell.exe or something
like that. Okay, so those three are very
useful to threat lockers ring fencing
core technology. Hope you enjoyed
learning how this is implemented. Check
out threat locker if you think your work
could benefit from something like that.
All right, let's go back to the show.
All right, dude. So uh I I actually have
a confession to make.
>> Uhhuh. So you [laughter]
don't uh me like that. So you you
remember on the pod a couple months ago
when I said I'll never give a talk ever
again.
>> Yes.
>> So I accidentally gave a talk.
>> You already did it. You already did it.
>> I already gave a talk at zero trustworld
and it was so much fun, dude. Oh my
gosh, it was great. And uh like
obviously Thread Locker is great. They
sponsor the pod. They're they're they're
really um instrumental to what we do
here on the pod. But that conference is
freaking great, man. Is it massive?
Yeah. And my my talk I just can I brag
on it for just a second course. Like I
was so pleased because I I I roll up
there and I I like you know get
everything set up and then the people
start coming in and the people start
coming in and they they gave laptops to
every participant too at the workshops.
Like the laptops were sitting in the
seats you know that were there for them
to use. You don't take them home but
like you know they they prepared them
for you in advance. They imaged them and
everything. So anyway, all of the seats
fill up and then uh there's still a lot
long line of people and then they come
up that you know the the threat locker
team comes up and they're like, "Hey
Justin, uh sorry to do this to you, but
the line is like around the corner
still. We need to put you in this bigger
room." So, like last minute before the
talk starts, we move like 400 people to
this next room, you know, and then that
room fills up and there's people
standing in the back and uh the turnout
was awesome and the crowd was so
engaged, man. They were like doing the
labs uh like along we we had more than
half of the people, you know, raised
their hands saying I finished the lab,
you know,
>> uh which was sick.
>> What was the lab?
>> So,
>> okay, so the lab was and this this is
where I'm sorry, thank you for bringing
me back around there. This is where all
all of this comes comes back to which
was
>> the reason I don't didn't want to do
talks is because I freaking hate
prepping slides.
>> Yeah, you don't want to prep, right?
>> But just like you said, all you do is
you write an outline in a MD file and
then you just give it to Cloud Code and
it just builds a website with for you
with all of your slides on it. And that
is the best for us as hackers because
not only is like
>> are you dealing with HTML rather than
like drag this element here, you know,
that sort of thing. Uh but you also can
just build the the labs in like the
interactive workshop directly into the
slides.
>> Oh, that's dope.
>> It's awesome, dude. It's freaking
awesome. And uh it was so fun to
present. No issues. You know, you just
drop it on a VPS. Yeah.
>> It's all, you know, more or less static.
So it's like, okay, you 500 people brute
forcing on it at the same time is not
going to cause a problem or whatever.
Yeah.
>> Um,
>> so anyway, dude, that's awesome.
>> I I'm back. I'm back. I I do kind of
like giving talk. I love giving talks
and the slide prep is not that bad
anymore, so I'm very pleased.
>> Okay. I do have to give you a hard time,
though. Did I see something that said
you signed some stickers?
>> Okay. Yes.
>> Okay. Famous Justin. People are gonna
collect your signed stickers.
>> Listen, man. Listen. That was shout out
to Everett, head of partnerships. He's
like, "Hey, man. I'm going to buy this
this Sharpie that we need to sign the
stickers." And actually, people really
liked that, though. So, after after the
uh the talk, you know, I they were like,
we gave out a couple signed stickers
with with codes, you know, to get free
swag for CTB on them. And then people
were coming up afterwards like, "Hey,
can you sign the sticker? Can you sign
the sticker?" And I'm like, "Okay." You
know, and so I don't know.
>> That's cool. No, I actually really like
my uh I think um Network Chuck for you
and I both like wrote like DC the date
last year when he gave us like Network
Chuck stickers and I that's like one of
my favorite stickers on my laptop. Yeah,
>> I will say it is kind of wearing off so
we need another one Chuck if you see
this. But
>> yeah. Yeah, the silver the silver
Sharpie is the way to go apparently
according to Everett. So um yeah, really
great conference. I'm I'm definitely
going to go back next year. Uh I thought
it was a blast and the venue was really
good. Threat Locker killed it on how
they put it on. Um, and so I'm going to
go back and and I really like that it
has aspects of like there's definitely
some more like corporate cyber security
stuff there, but then there's also like
literally hands on the keyboard hacking
stuff labs as well, right? So, I think
it's like a good like CISO and
technical, you know, conference, which I
think is pretty rare. It's one or the
other typically.
>> That's dope. Also, by the way, if you
hear like hammering or tile cutting, we
have contractors upstairs. So,
>> dude, I also have contractors upstairs
right now.
That's funny. We're hopefully Richard,
try your best with this episode, man.
>> Yeah, I'm going to try to mute between
stuff, but we'll see.
>> Yeah. All right. Um, we got a couple of
time. Yeah.
>> Yeah. Not a lot of time. So, let's let's
jump through it. You you're up first.
>> Okay. [snorts] Sweet. Um, I mean, a lot
of a lot of this uh episode don't don't
let it scare you away. I think it'll be
really interesting. You know, obviously
I've often been talking about hacking
AI, but this is going to be about using
AI to hack. not the not the whole
episode, but a lot of my content is. And
I and I'm doing that honestly because it
feels like it's in the zeitgeist, which
if people don't know what that means,
it's like that's what's in the culture
right now. Like if you're on X,
everyone's just like blowing up talking
about using ad hack and there's like
overreactions and there's bad takes and
there's like good takes. And so anyways,
a bunch of the things I'm going to
mention are like relevant to that. Um
our boy Sweetly or Sweet Lie, however
you want to pronounce it. [snorts] Um
updated BBcope. He has like a website
and like he updated the open source
code. So if you don't want to use the
website, you can just like spin up your
own instance of it. But um I've always
loved this. I you know where I'm kind of
like a recon guy and love big fuzzing.
I've always loved BBScope to just like
dump all this all of the scope for like
because you know there are uh things
like is it adiches like targets BBcope
something GitHub that's like useful for
all the public programs but if you want
all of your privates which is really you
know where often things are more likely
to be found you can use BBcope to dump
that. Um, and the like hacker one a
while back added like an API key so
you're not using something sketchy where
you're like pasting in your cookies and
all that. Um, and so anyways, he has a
big new upgrade and I think you shared
with me a link right before this which
we'll drop it in the show notes that um,
there was a pull request like he
released this like a couple days ago and
then as of like today there's no pull
request that allows you actually just
dump your reports which can be which can
be really useful. Now there is some
drama around that uh, also if you want
to get into that about whether you
should give your reports.
>> I don't know. I don't know. I think I
think it's good. I think exactly what
you did and what Corbin did as well
where you just you dump your reports and
you you say Claude go build yourself a
set of skills to implement the
techniques that are referenced in this
report. I think that is really really
good idea. I haven't done it yet
personally but
>> well well Tommy's big push back against
that is that we don't have the right to
share it with third parties. So Tommy
was going at me on on X our last guest
which by the way if you haven't seen
that episode it's awesome. Go check it
out. Yeah, you know Tommy's obviously
due to his past a very a very by the
book person these days right like he is
very much by the book and I you know my
personal belief is that if you've got
you know if you've set it in the
settings for major model providers that
you trust like Google open athropic that
they can't train on your data I don't
think there's any risk with like
importing your reports to cloud code or
codeex whatever to have it try to bypass
or to find adjacent bugs to that or to
build skills Um, if we get some if we
get some sort of top down direction that
we shouldn't do that, then maybe it's a
different discussion. But anyways, that
that's the drama around that part.
>> Yeah, dude. I I I think it's I mean I
think that we put these HTTP requests
into Kaido, you know, we put these
requests into Burp, you know, like there
there are obviously it's different when
it's going up to the cloud or whatever,
but like they're hosting stuff in AWS,
right? You know, a hacker one is, right?
So there there's third parties going to
be involved in here, right? Um,
>> and as long as there's some legal
protection there around like, you know,
they're not allowed to train on it. And,
um, I just don't think that there's any
chance that they're going to be going
through the, you know, tens of trillions
of tokens to go find like my report, you
know, like it just it seems silly,
>> right? Yeah.
>> Like get get your head out of the
freaking like I'm the main character
vibe here. Like no one gives a [__]
about your bug bounty reports. Like it's
exactly like if you've got some crazy
like zero day on Android, you know, then
okay, maybe you need to be careful, you
know, like a like one of those $2.5
million chains.
>> If you have a Pegasus if you have a
Pegasus exploit, like maybe be careful.
>> Yeah. But like really if you're not in
possession of something like that,
>> no one gives a [__] dude. Like about
you, you know, like
>> and I really
>> And I'm saying that as a higher profile
individual, like no one gives [__] about
me. [laughter]
>> Like it's it's Yeah. And I think what
Alex said was really eye opening too
that we do actually retain full IP to
our reports. And so in some ways I think
we do have um you know some types of um
rights. I don't know exactly, you know,
where all those boundaries are, but I
think that it is at the end of the day
still our IP. It is oftentimes the
company's IP also for their use, but it
still is also ours. So
>> dude, I actually just logged into
claiming
data-privacy-controls and turned off
those those little
>> Yeah.
>> little things. I haven't done that yet,
so I'm glad you reminded me to do that.
If you guys haven't done that, you could
just log into cloud.ai, go to your
settings, go to the privacy tab, and
turn those off. Um,
>> yeah, and maybe do that for each of your
subs if you have multiple.
>> Exactly. Who knows if you have multiple.
You You certainly don't have multiple,
Joseph. So,
>> yeah, I've never mentioned that. No, I
actually have three. Three right now,
but I'm hoping to keep scaling up. So,
>> I feel like you're not allowed to say
that, bro.
>> Okay, never mind. I don't have that
many. [laughter]
>> Anthropic is like I'm sorry, what' you
say? Um, yeah. So, all right, man. Well,
that's good. Um, I actually, as their
next topic, just wanted to give a shout
out to uh our boy Matt Brown, who
recently announced that he was going
full-time and, you know, pulled the
trigger, did it job.
>> Yeah. Is a full-time um, you know,
pentest, content creator, bug bounty
hunter, that sort of thing. So, if you
guys haven't seen his channel, um,
you're definitely going to want to go
check it out. We'll link it in the
description. He's NMAT0
on uh, Twitter.
And um yeah, his content is just the
best content out there around for IoT
device hacking in my opinion.
>> Yeah. And and you know, I think that
this is very resilient and important.
Like obviously I think for for being
resilient and bug bounty, I think that
you can look at games, look at desktop
apps. Uh you know, there are things you
can do to stay more resilient as like AI
stuff kind of picks up. But I think
going into hardware hacking is one of
the smartest plays you can do if you
have the time and the bandwidth to do
it. And his YouTube channel is gold.
like it's just the best at hardware
hacking um on YouTube. And so and he's
one of the boys, you know, he's you
know, he's he's been around the live
hacking event scene. He's really cool.
We got to support our support our
friends. So
>> yeah, and and uh I will say one of the
things he announced in his video was
that he is also doing training stuff by
mass request. Um so he has two uh
courses out there right now. Digital
signal analysis for hardware hackers and
beginner's guide to IoT and hardware
hacking. Um, and guys, these are grossly
grossly underpriced.
>> Uh, these are like $200 and $50.
>> Oh gosh.
>> Uh, so yeah, I got to hit up my boy and
be like, "What are you doing?"
>> Uh, like, but yeah, definitely go check
those out. We're going to give away a
couple subscriptions uh to this critical
thinkers tier on Discord uh as a way to
support Matt as he uh starts his
endeavors here. But definitely a good
place to get started with uh for
hardware hacking if that's the route you
want to go.
>> Yeah. Yeah. And if you have any hardware
stuff or want any type of pentest, like
he does contract pin test. So if you're
a company, definitely reach out to Matt.
>> Yeah. Um All right. What you got next?
>> Uh the second thing is probably short,
so you might have me skip it. But
original sick sec on X. Uh I feel like,
um
>> people have maybe seen that before. Are
you going to share? You want me to
share?
>> No, no, go for it, man.
>> Oh man, I'm logged in. Um anyway,
>> oh share your screen.
>> Yeah, it's fine. I like to let you share
or people can look it up themselves.
Anyways,
>> I got you. I got you.
>> Another bug bounty hunter who built a
MCP style client for um accessing and
listening to reports and stuff.
Honestly, I was going to share this
before Sweetly Upgraded his BBcope. Um
I'd rather have it all in one tool. So,
I'll probably just use BBcope, but if
anybody wants to use like a MCP for
Hacker One to search your reports and
that sort of thing, that's a good one to
do. Okay. Uh yeah. So, my main thing um
and this is like actually I'm going to
let you go first. I'll I'll let that be
my second small one. Um you go first
because my the rest of mine are all kind
of around the same topic. Um Okay.
>> So, yeah. And that'll be like a bigger
>> discuss. Yeah, sure. I got you. So, um
the next item that I had to share on the
list was I've just been having a lot of
success lately on Google with ProtoBuff
related stuff. Okay. And and and
obviously there's like this protojson
stuff that they're doing where you know
uh they're removing the fields. It's
kind of like protobuff but but in JSON
format. That is a necessity. You've got
to know how to deal with that if you're
going to hack on Google at all. That's
not what I'm talking about. What I'm
talking about is the actual protobuff
stuff. Like there are a lot of
parameters that are B64 encoded like you
know binary protocol protobuff stuff. Um
and I think a lot of people just get
scared of it and assume it's signed or
you know uh just don't mess with it. Um,
and I've been messing with it and it's
been giving me some good stuff. Uh, so I
built a little Kaido uh, convert
workflow which I'll drop in the Discord.
Um, that allows you to just in line
inside of Kaido uh, decrypt those uh, or
I shouldn't say decrypt denode decode
those um, uh, Protobuff B6 C4 encoded
strings. Okay.
>> And and then you can just kind of look
at them. They're not going to have the
key the key values, right? That's the
the sad thing about Protobuff is just
just has the value. But um you can look
at the value and kind of extrapolate
what's going on there. Uh and so you'll
see nested protobuff. So protobuff
inside of protobuff. And uh you know,
I'm not going to lie, it does get to be
a little bit of a pain. But if you de,
you know, decode all of that stuff and
you look deep into it, you'll find ids,
you'll find, you know, strings that you
that you see get manifested in the UI.
Uh and those things have some really
really crazy impact once you start
understanding it.
>> Yeah. It actually unlocks the ability to
hack stuff that you kind of weren't able
to like even like test before.
>> Yeah, absolutely. And I did want to give
just a really quick um explanation of
how Protobby Protobuff stuff works here.
Um they've got a a bunch of different
you know features of Protobuff. But one
of the things that I wanted to mention
was that uh there there are you know
length delimited strings, right? So you
can say okay I've got the string it's
this length and it's you know sort of
standard binary protocol like that but
um they also encode the wire type a
field number and continuation flag
inside of it um and that's kind of what
the you know single eight bits
recommend uh represents there. So I I'll
explain very briefly the first three
bits are the wire type. So this is like
oh you got a a var you've got a string
you've got a you know a fixed integer
size um that's going to be encoded in
those first three bits in the next four
bits you've got the actual field number
that is associated with this content. So
if you have the protobuff um
representation, you can map, you know,
the key names back to the values. But if
not, you're just going to get the
>> field number that is associated with
this specific value, right?
>> Um and that takes uh No, that's f.
>> Uh no, that's five. five
>> four bits.
>> The last bit is uh the continuation
>> which allows you to continue expanding
that metadata and then um you've got
your actual data representation. So it's
a it's a little bit complex but once you
kind of wrap your head around it, it's
not too bad. You got to familiarize
yourself with the um different variable
types and stuff like that. uh and all of
that gets extracted away by this Kaido
convert workflow that I use and just
allows me to see okay you know field one
maps to this string field two maps to
this integer that sort of thing and if
you just have even that rudimentary
level understanding of it then you can
really pop some cool bugs if you can
reverse you know write take cloud code
and say hey re write me something that
reverses this uh and then you can inject
into those various fields does that does
that make sense
>> yeah yeah know it makes sense
>> yeah and cloud is so good at it, man.
Every time you hand it a buffer, it's
like, "Oh, yeah, of course the the
Protobuff. Here's the Python script to"
and I'm like, "Thank you."
>> Yeah. And that wasn't true a year ago. I
actually wasn't.
>> Yeah. So, I've got a lot to say on that.
But on the topic of Kaido and I'm
wearing the Kaido shirt today um and
Cloud Code, we released by Sorry, we me
and Justin are advisers, but uh Kaido
released a Kaido skill for Cloud Code or
Codeex or whatever to plug into. It's at
github.com/kyosskills.
But there's also a blog that's getting
posted today and I'm posting a blog post
about it as well kind of addressing some
of the elephants in the room. Um but
yeah, actually do you know can that
skill yet uh it probably cannot because
workflows are kind of complex. It can't
edit workflows yet.
>> I don't think so. But that is something
we definitely want to build on the fly
is like hey letting it hook in there and
say hey build me a workflow to like
decrypt this protobuff like oh my gosh
>> or or implement this this workflow that
that Justin uh made like you know
install it for me in Kaido. [snorts]
>> But I will say though the I'm sorry
going back thing because it is sort of
relevant to that like if you do get
Claude to analyze these protobuff
strings and I'll I'll just say it
straight as I can here. This is a really
good area for you guys to use AI to find
bugs that were not really as accessible
a year ago without AI, right? Because
plot is very good at understanding these
protobuff structures. So you give it
this string and it can easily create you
a program to reverse those and and you
know re-encode them in the right format,
right? They do sometimes have checksums
for those in in Google's architecture
inside of those protobuffs. Uh, but
dude, clot is like a very high hit rate
of like being able to just look at it
and be like, "Oh, yeah, that clearly is
the check sum for this." So, I'll just
calculate that based off of the And I'm
like, whoa, okay. Um, so definitely a
good area to use those. And like you
were saying, if we can get AI to be able
to build workflows very easily inside of
Kaido. I think that'll be a big level
up, too. So, maybe I'll try to add that
to the skill within the next couple
weeks before this airs.
>> Yeah, it already has a ton of
functionality. So, um, Emil and Yan
added some really cool SDKs that are now
plugged into that skill. So, it can like
add findings, edit requests, search HTTP
history, like add match replace stuff. I
really want it to I really want them to,
and I think in the next release they're
going to add it, be able to mess with
the sitemap tree because I think it'd be
really cool to like um have some sort of
like coverage map where you and because
they're because they're adding plugin to
plugin um
>> plugin to plugin, what's that called?
Conversation.
>> Yeah. Well, no disc like uh not
compatibility. Anyways, the ability for
plugins to communicate. Communication is
the word I was looking for.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> Um and I think having like a sitemap
coverage tree would be so cool where it
like it puts the sitemap into like a
plugin and then it like marks them all
red and then like as you and Cloud Code
like add them to replay and test things,
it like turns them all green and so you
can be like, "Oh, I've definitively
tested all this." It makes me think of a
long time ago,
>> I heard that like Space Raccoon used to
do that like when especially when he
first got started. He would basically
list out every API endpoint and like
every query and then like all the bug
class he likes to check for and he would
have like a coverage map in Google
Sheets and he would just test every
single thing and then he would end up
finding a bunch of bugs that way because
he was way more thorough than anyone
else. Right.
>> That jerk man. You know, the same thing
that that Ronchan did that really like
messed with me was like he's like, "Oh
yeah, I just need you need to be so
thorough. You need to like test every
field and every value for every field of
every endpoint of every mutation of
every freaking I'm like dude like stop,
you know?" And uh I don't know. I'm
still so jaded from this one live
hacking event where I spent like an hour
on this one, you know, trying to exploit
this one endpoint and he popped in and
got arbitrary atto on like GitHub or
something or no on GitLab and this is
before he worked with them
>> and it was because you missed like a
single key, right?
>> Yeah. And it's like, you know, it's like
one of the weird, you know, values of
the GraphQL schema that like doesn't
look like it's going to do anything, so
you don't even really check it, but then
it like completely bypasses the whole
off scheme. It's like
but yeah um dude thoroughess is
important
>> on that exact same topic because it's
like just relevant to all of this cloud
code when hacking for um me and XSS
doctor basically found a high or maybe
it's a critical on like a a major
company by looking at like the survey
endpoints like that's just the stuff
that I always ignore you know like this
just stuff that's like feedback
submission survey junk same things with
same thing with those headers that there
was like that big finding on last year
like trace headers or It's like these
things that like we get so used to as
bug hunters uh used to ignoring that
sometimes, you know, Claude or um
whatever we're using, we'll end up
testing. So,
>> dude, are you even hacking anymore, bro?
Are you just like directing Claude?
Like, every time I hear you talking
about it, you're just like directing
Claude.
>> Yeah, I feel like my job is more triage
and validation like over the last six
weeks.
>> It's crazy. And I and I mean I don't
think that it in any way I mean I'm sure
over time it will degrade skills but in
general I find that it's it's like uh
leveling up my heristic for like where
to look and what to look at and it's
also
um yeah it's just finding stuff that I
would that I would have not found right
and so it's expanding my scope and my
understanding of these applications
especially on big targets like Google
like just the random gadgets and
information it finds about
architecturally about these targets
levels up my understanding
architecturally where even if cloud code
were to go away, I now understand
Google's infrastructure way better.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I think that is the plus. I
will say that I have found myself
becoming a little bit lazy though. Oh
yeah. Like the the other day I like a
buddy of mine found a CSS injection and
I was like, "Oh yeah, dude. I'll just
use like my stuff to hack this and I was
like, "Oh man, I'm going to have to like
set up the font leak and the liatures
and all right, let me go do it." And I
started doing I was like, "Oh, I'll have
Claude do it." And then I spent like two
hours trying to get Claude to do it and
Claude couldn't do it.
>> Oh, you could have just done it.
>> No, I know. I could have just done it
myself and I'm like, "No, I'm just going
to like get Claude to do it." And then
it like, you know, and then you run it
for the first five minutes and and and
it's like, "Oh, wow. It's doing
everything. Like, this is going to be so
fast." And then something's off and but
you have no idea what because you didn't
do any of it, you know, and it's like,
>> "Dang it." Uh, so I don't know.
Sometimes you get big wins, but
sometimes there's misses on that as
well, I think.
>> Yeah. All right, dude. Here's the major
topic. You got one more thing before I
jump to this whole major topic.
>> Okay. Yeah, I do. Okay. [clears throat]
Um, so I wanted to mention as well, and
I I've mentioned this, I think, briefly
on the pod before, but I've actually
been finding a lot of permissions
issues, client side bugs recently, and I
wanted to mention a chain that is uh
that is pretty good that maybe people
can use. So, um, one of the vans I found
recently was a sea surf of sorts to
start recording with the victim's mic.
Uh, and then you know what would happen
is if after a certain period of time, it
would take whatever you said, transcribe
it, and put it into their service,
right?
>> Okay.
>> And and so I was like, okay, well, if I
go to the site and I click allow, you
know, allow this site to always access
my microphone or whatever, um, then this
doesn't require any user interaction at
all. You could it can just start
recording your microphone at any time.
Um so what I did is I I did a login
seurf to my own account.
>> Wow.
>> Then then I you know audio record curfed
uh the endpoint to start recording.
>> Sick.
>> And then after a certain period of time
it would you know cut the recording and
and then upload it to my account.
>> It's in your account. Yeah.
>> Right. So now I can just effectively spy
on the user. Um and yeah it's I mean it
it seems to hit pretty well. I've
reported this a couple times now and it
and you know they care about this. Um I
think it's a little bit of a flaw with
the whole concept of like domain locked
permissions
>> because
>> it almost needs to be account locked,
right?
>> It it does it needs to be account
locked, right? Because if if you know
>> Yeah. basically this is like a really
>> it but like you know
is going to be on my account. If it's on
my account I'm fine with it recording,
right? But if it if somebody log in
seurfs their own account, then I'm going
to, you know, now I'm just uploading
data into somebody else's account, you
know, and it's this is not good.
>> Well, I just love it because I think
that taking a gadget like like CE like
login curve and turning into something
impactful is really cool.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So anyway, and then there's
also the the concept that I've talked
about before of like permission
delegation down into iframes. like
whenever you're seeing an iframe that
you can control, make sure you check the
permissions, you know, the allow um
attribute on that to like know whether
it's allowing like screen recording, mic
recording, any of those things. And that
whether those permissions are being
delegated from the top level frame down
into the iframe and if it is, then you
might be able to abuse those as a third
party iframe inside of a trusted tople
page.
>> Right. Yeah, I remember you'd mentioned
that. What's the name of that attribute
again? Yeah, I think it's like the I'm
gonna go pull it up right now, but it's
like the allow allow iframe permissions.
Pull it up on MDN.
>> Yeah, the allow property. Yeah, we the
allow property of the HTML iframe
element indicates the permissions policy
specified for this iframe.
>> So, yeah, that's the one.
>> All right, dude. So, in a private
Discord that you and I are in, I've had
lots of discussions. I had these same
discussions back whenever AI was like
getting a little bit better at coding
and it was like getting better at image
gen and video gen. You know, I was
always like in there hyping it up as I
as I as the hype man that I am. But um I
would get some push back, you know,
like, oh, I can definitely tell this is
AI and that sort of thing. And it
eventually kind of passed. You know, of
course, you can still tell sometimes
when things are AI, but it is getting
harder. But anyways, now that discussion
has now kind of moved into over the last
like week or two, can AI hack things,
right? And I'm sure if you're on X at
all, you've probably seen all these
discussions. People are blowing up
tweets like, "I found this with cloud
code and I found that with cloud code."
And it's brought out in my opinion a
couple different like um thoughts. And
these are these are in my most recent
blog post that I just put up on on the
site. Um but the the thoughts that um I
often feel compelled to believe are
things like even my grandma could do it,
right? Um, and there was some like
really cheesy AI slop about my grandma
finding a bug, you know, not not
literally mine, but the the person who
was posting it.
Sorry for hitting my mic. And um, and I,
you know, and I think that I am like I
tend to overestimate what other people
can do, especially people who don't have
our skill set for like our
understanding, for how we see bug
bounty, how we see life, how we see
coding, how we sell Cervers. And in
fact, you know, in building like small
AI apps um, for just like friends and
family, when someone says thank you, I'm
like, "Ah, don't worry about it. Claude
did it. And my wife's like, "Stop saying
that." Like, sure, that's kind of true,
but you know how to host a server. You
know how to tell it what to do. You know
like how it should build it. And then
when things don't work, you know how to
fix it. Like you're basically leveraging
all of your technical expertise to like
actually make this possible, right? And
so I kind of disagree with that though,
dude. Like totally I agree with you, but
like Claude can also do the hosting now.
Like you can literally just say like
host it,
>> you know, and then it will go do that,
you know? I did that for the zero trust
world thing. I was like,
>> but when you say host, it's going to say
like where do you mean to host it?
Right? And so like for somebody who's
nontechnical, it's going to say like,
okay, well, do you have a virtual server
anywhere? And when grandma says no, it's
going to be like, okay, well, you need
to go sign up on this website, right?
And then get me an API key. It's like we
know what API keys are. We know how to
sign up for websites. we know and like
that that is a low barrier entry but
what I'm saying what I'm trying to say
here is I think that
>> when I say you know kind of anyone can
do it I'm talking about like anyone with
knowledge of APIs and servers and who
has done some hacking right and at that
and at that point I think I'm 1000%
correct but I don't think that like
anyone can do it right
>> so okay I so yes I agree but I think the
difference between you and you and I who
are like spending like time deploying
stuff hacking things you know very
technical in the weeds, right? And my
friend Tobias, who is uh, you know,
business IT automation, you know, is
what he loves to do.
>> The the gap between me and him just got
a lot smaller
>> because because he he can now say to
Claude, "Okay, yeah, you need a VPS, I
got you. Here's, you know, the the IP
address and I set the password to this.
Log in." And then it just logs in and
does it, right? You know, he can do
that. Yeah. you know, he can go grab an
API key and and and you know, if you get
give it an API key for Digital Ocean,
it'll just get the domain, it'll grab
the thing, you know, it can do all of
that, right? Um, so I don't know. I on
on one hand, certainly that's true, but
but I think the gap for between him and
and us just got a lot smaller, and I
also think it superpowers us, you know,
to be able to do things like the gap
between me and the person that invented
Protobuff, you know, like you know,
there's there's tears to this and I
think Claude helps helps, you know, take
people that have a general knowledge of
something and be able to actually
implement it, which is really beautiful.
>> Yeah. No, I agree. And I think and I
think that for the I think for anyone
who is just like slightly further down,
they can just keep asking like, "Okay,
well, how do I do that?" Okay, well, how
do I do that? And when everybody's in
that mindset, it really does um level
everyone up. But the other thing that
kind of hit me was like um so let's say
your your buddy your IT buddy spins it
he spins up a VPS he's using cloud code
he's getting into bug bounty he's like
okay go find these bugs all right so now
what's the next limiting factor the next
limiting factor is he doesn't know what
is a false positive and so this is
another thing this is another thing that
actually Patrick pointed out to me
>> and it's and you know because I'm kind
of like I kind of hate the fact that
like any salesperson right now could
just go use cloud code make a hackbot
and then go like rip a bunch local
businesses off like running his packbot
as like a pentest as a service and
selling pentest, right? But I think that
the difference um and obviously business
owners can't differentiate this, but the
the real difference between that and
what I'm doing or what you're doing is
that we do know, right? When when it
when it when it says jackpot critical
finding, we're like, yeah, that's just a
wild card course and it's not
>> there's a chance it's actually valid.
Yeah.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. And I do think um
if you are building this and you're
having those issues, the pro tip here is
basically play whack-a-ole with those
errors, right? As you run it over the
next week, go back and look at the false
positives and incorporate those back
into the prompt. Like, hey, when you
found this, it was a false positive
because of this. When you found this,
you said it was a critical on my rating.
That's more like a low or medium. I
still reported it, but like you know,
like basically play whack-a-ole with the
issues it has and it will improve. And
so, I think that that's that's a good
tip. But I do think that that's another
place where our intelligence is baked in
um to what we just expect of others but
that they might not be able to actually
have or do because it often will even
take me a while to fully gro and to
fully validate some of these bugs. Um
and it's because they're like weird
ones, right? It's like it's not using my
knowledge. It has knowledge about stuff
that I don't even understand, right? And
so then I have to go understand and
figure that out.
>> Now we understand what it feels like to
be a triager, [laughter] you know, where
they're like, "Oh, we just got this
report." Like I don't being a triagger I
think is a really crazy skill, you know,
like you've got to be able to, you know,
figure out the threat model, look at
this person's attack vector that you've
never heard of before,
>> figure out if it's valid, you know, it's
it's pretty cool. Um, but yeah, I I
don't know, man. I I think one of the
areas I'm underusing Cloud right now is
like getting more customization and
playing whack-a-ole, like you said. Like
I'll often just really rely on like very
few things that I have in my cloud MD
File
a handful of skills and then just spend
most of the time actually just
explaining to it.
>> Okay. Well, that what to do.
>> Okay. Well, stop. Let me fix that for
you. It It's going to take like three
lines. Really, it makes a big
difference. You just need to add to your
cloud MD. Anytime I get frustrated or
anytime I have to reexlain something to
you to you that you did not understand
or anytime that you like try one command
and it fails and you try another command
and it fails, add that to the applied
learning section in your Claude MD and
it will literally grow. Like every time
you use Claude, it improves. It's like a
self-improving loop that will then level
up your own local Claude that will make
it much better.
>> What? What? [sighs] Okay.
>> Are you mad you didn't do this? Do you
disagree with what is it?
>> No, I just I just like I don't know,
man. I like I don't really I like I feel
like is it going to know what things I
want to have it improve on? Like I don't
get frustrated with cloud. I don't say
like listen here you dummy. You know,
like I I I tell it, "Hey, do this." And
I try to, you know, I don't know.
>> Okay, here's here's what I noticed when
I'm using it. I'll say, "Hey, go pull up
whatever that we were working on last
week. Go find it." And what will it do?
It'll run like 20 different bash
commands. It'll try to find it in some
places. It'll try to use this thing.
It'll use too wide of a thing. It'll
find too many files. It'll find too few.
Right? Ever since I added that thing
that I just told you now, what it does,
like once it's like had to try something
and got a bunch of errors or not found
what it's looking for, it will then
update information. It'll be like, you
know, when Joseph asked me to look for
session files in claude, they're located
includes. Right now, the next time I ask
it to search, it only searches once. And
so it basically improved itself which
saves tokens and then like saves
frustration, saves time.
>> Okay. All right. All right. Fine. I'll
give it a shot. I'll [laughter] add it.
All right. Um Okay. Be before we before
we we close though, um
one of the things I did want to discuss
was I think there's this whole concept
of like token FOMO right now where
people are like, I should be really
really utilizing my Cloud Max
subscription to the absolute max. I
think you're doing a great job of that.
Um they integrated CL uh cloud RC which
is something that I was really looking
forward to with um like just being able
to take your cloud session and you know
resume it on your phone and give it
instructions in the real time but it
doesn't support dangerously skip
permissions which is something that you
essentially have to use if you're using
cloud because it's like it's going to
run 50 bash commands you know and you're
like I don't want to press yes every
single time like I want you to sit in
this container that I've got you in
>> and and then do whatever the heck you
want in my little container, you know.
Um, so I don't know, man. Do you have
any good solution for that? I was kind
of disappointed by RC.
>> Uh, I just haven't needed it. I didn't
need OpenClaw or RC. And it's
specifically because I just deployed a
Discord bot that creates a thread and in
that thread, it's the same thing as a
cloud session. So, I just have a private
Discord server. I just
>> What do you just like about this?
>> Doesn't look as good though, right? Like
>> Oh, it looks great. Let me see if I can
take a good screenshot and share it with
you all. Uh, I want to do it very
quickly, but basically
>> put it put it in the dock or something
because Yeah, maybe.
>> Yeah, I'll put it in the dock, but
basically what
>> redact it.
>> Yeah, that's fine. What it looks like
is, have you ever even seen this? This
is a little pro tip for the listeners,
too. Did you know that uh Discord has a
diff um code block type?
>> Ah,
>> send me a message. Send me a message to
Discord. Actually, everyone listening
along in Discord, do back tick backtick
diff. And then have some lines with a
plus and some lines with a minus. The
lines with a plus will be green. The
lines with a minus will be red.
>> Oh, interesting.
Wow. What the heck,
>> dude? It's beautiful. And you can So,
you can just have it write that out. So,
I have mine write out all the tool
calls, all the things. Let me see if I
can um show you.
>> You don't have to redact in real time.
You can just put it in the doc and then
we'll redact it afterwards. And
>> Okay. Yeah. Well, let me when I show you
what this looks like, you're going to be
like, uh, I need that. I'm gonna put it
in the dock and Yeah, we'll just put it
Yeah, that's true. We can just like do a
overlay or I can even find a better
picture. Okay, I just put in the doc.
What do you think? This is what this is
what my threads look like.
>> Yeah, that looks pretty good, man.
>> Yeah, you can see exactly what it's
running. And I even have it snip if it's
too long.
>> And um and I and I have it where I can
like send audio messages in. So like
>> What about control O?
>> Control O. Oh, to show more. Yeah, I
can't do control O, but I do have things
like um you know how you can control C
if it's like going down a rabbit hole?
>> Yeah,
>> you just you just send in like a stop
command, it stops it. Um,
>> okay.
>> Yeah. So,
>> and you just had it code up this bot for
you?
>> Yeah, I had to code up this bot. I would
maybe be willing to share it. I'll think
about that. But either way, I mean
anyway,
>> there's plenty of solutions out there,
I'm sure.
>> Yeah. And I will say you have to write
custom handlers for like each tool call
type. So, let me show you this in the
doc. Um, basically what I'm showing for
the listeners only is that you know how
there's a todo write and like a todo
read. So, I have mine use emojis for
like the todo right. So, like right
here, you can see it. It's already
finished all the the tutors at the top
and it's working on the bottom one. And
so, it updates that as it goes and it
writes that out.
>> Um,
>> wait, does it go back and update the
message
>> or does it write a new to-do list every
time?
>> No, it's writing a new to-do list. Yeah,
but it doesn't matter because I'm just
watching the bottom anyways. And at the
at the top of these um new threads, I
have it give me the d-res. So, if I need
to go like jump on this on the BPS, I
have a copy and pasteable command to
jump straight into this session.
>> What are you so skeptical for? This is
great. I can just hack from my phone
basically like with continue. Oh yeah,
sorry. I have that too. So if I do slash
my Discord bot um resume, I can paste in
the resume. So this is basically like
the RC continue or remote control.
>> Sure.
>> From my local U machine or from my VPS
and it will resume that session. So then
I can walk away and keep going.
>> Wait, do you have this running on your
local machine and on your VPS?
>> Um no, the bot doesn't actually have
access to local. So, it's only you could
do the same thing if you wanted to, but
it would have to pick it up from local
or SCP it or something.
>> But,
>> yeah. All right, man. I don't know. I I
I just like I It's not good. The cloud
interface, the cloud code interface on
the phone is not good. It It's It's bad,
but it looks how I want it to look.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, like, and it feels how I want
it to feel, but like the implementation
is really bad.
>> Here's the here's the diffs, by the way,
since we're about to end. Um, here's
like the type of diffs it writes
whenever it's updating stuff for me.
>> Oh, wow. Dang. That's super gorgeous.
>> I know. It's actually It's actually
easier on the eyes than the than the um
TUI.
>> Dang. Okay. All right. Maybe that that
one I'll give you a maybe on. I will
definitely go add to my cloud MD file,
you know, the self-improvement loop
thing. But uh
>> well, here's the thing about the Discord
bot. You don't have to use it. Like what
it's really useful for is a lot of times
on my VPS, like let's say I'm out and
about and you know, somebody messages me
as like, "Hey, here's this critical
thing. Can you validate it real quick?"
I will then just like pull up my phone,
pull up Discord, do like start a new
session in that new thread and just be
like, "Hey, validate this for me." Or
I'll say like, "Hey, you know, my my
website went down. Can you check out
like check the logs real quick, check
the errors?" It's kind of like my DevOps
engineer on speed dial in Discord where
I'm already at anyways when I'm out and
about when I don't have my computer. And
so I can both hack from remote or check
on things via remote or download things
or I can say like host this from my
friend at this path and I can do all of
that without my computer.
>> Yeah. But like can you do that? Like
does it take images? Does it take voice
recording and stuff like that? Because
even with Claudebot I had issues with
that back in the day.
>> Yeah. No day being like three weeks ago
when got popular. [laughter]
>> No mine mine does accept um attachments
>> and it does accept voice. Um, I don't
have it accepting images, but I mean it
would be mostly trivial trivial to use.
I just never have to give it images. So,
>> yeah, that makes sense. All right, man.
We'll see. We'll give it a shot. I feel
like this episode was like a bunch of us
talking about Cloud, but the world is
really changing, man, with the way that
it works with uh with bug bounty stuff
right now. I think
>> Yeah, actually, let me let me respond to
that with the like even though we're
going over by like one minute here. I do
have to go pick up my my daughter. But I
I think that people who are annoyed by
us talking about AI or AI hacking like
they're just like they are just they did
they're just missing out or they're just
being um like grumpy about it because
like even even if you're only going to
use it to just write code for you to
like reproduce something or even if
you're only going to use it to host a PC
like you're silly to not to not use it
for some things like that, right? Or
even if you're only going to use it for
reversing RPC like let's you don't have
to use it as your full-blown hackbot if
you don't want to. Like I know Bus
Factor, he like just really wants to be
human in the loop with it, right? But it
found him a high on a program that pays
8K for highs last night and before that
he was kind of like skeptical, didn't
really like it, was kind of just like
piecing it together or copying and
pasting from chat bots. And now I think
he's probably going to be hooked because
that one bug will pay for his usage for
three years, right? And
>> um and there's no doubt it's going to
get better. So that's one thing I didn't
get to mention was, you know, I think
the reason why this is so possible like
Hackbots worked a year ago, right? expo
or whatever like companies were able to
do some stuff with it but you had to
have a bunch of like specialized uh
rappers specialized prompts and the
reason for that was because the models
were not that smart you needed the
internal monologue of experts or good
reports in the context you don't need
that anymore because claude opus 46 even
saw at 46 and I think Douglas Dman using
haiku and finding bugs with it he's
found like five figures worth of bugs
like in the last couple weeks and he's
using like mostly haiku is because they
went in cyberbench from like 30% to like
69% of pass rate. What this means is the
models actually understand hacking
better than they ever have before on
this most recent release. And so
anyways, people can be skeptical, people
can be mad. I don't really care. I think
that this is going to continue to impact
our industry and it you have the
opportunity to really like level up and
make more money this year, more bugs.
Um, and people should do it. So
>> yeah. Yeah. Well, GG, man. I I think
that's true. And I think, you know, just
a moment ago, I I sort of had that
experience with with Shift a while back,
you know, and I got that 15k bounty. And
every time I I just recently had to go
and uh refill my open router with
credits. I was like, "Oh, man. Do I put
another 200 bucks on here?" And I'm
like, "Wait a second. This has already
paid for itself time and time and time
and time again, you know. So, yeah, it's
definitely worth it." All right, let's
let's make let's uh let's call it a wrap
then. Yeah.
>> Perfect. Yep. Peace, guys.
>> Peace. Good pod.
And that's a wrap on this episode of
Critical Thinking. Thanks so much for
watching to the end, y'all. If you want
more critical thinking content, [music]
uh, or if you want to support the show,
head over to ctbb.show/isord.
You can hop in the community. There's
lots of great highlevel [music] hacking
discussion happening there on top of
master classes, hackalongs, exclusive
content, and a full-time hunters guild.
If you're a full-time hunter, it's a
great time. [music] Trust me. All right,
I'll see you there.